<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/8/2014 2:58:35 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TURRET">
			<Text>Turret Control</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SUSPEND">
			<Text>Suspension Room</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_NEURO">
			<Text>Neurotoxin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_FAC">
			<Text>Sciance Facility</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_APT_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Aperturian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_APT_DESC">
			<Text>Apature Sciance</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_APT_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Apature</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_APT_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_APT_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				ADD TEXT
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GLADOS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GLADOS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				GLaDOS (Genetic Lifeform and Disk Operating System) is a fictional artificially intelligent computer system who  is responsible for testing
				and maintenance in Aperture Science research facility.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE}It is believed that the GLaDOS project was used in 1982, where
				version 1.07, and later 1.07a and 1.09, operated Aperture Science's Enrichment Centre Test Subject Application Process. Aperture also started
				using a bulletin board system in 1973, which was later managed by GLaDOS as late as 1997.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1986, construction of the first
				iteration of GLaDOS began in the Enrichment Centre with the aim of accelerating the Portal project, and beating their rival company, Black Mesa.
				A prototype chassis for GLaDOS was constructed in 1989, but was subsequently abandoned. In 1996, after a decade spent bringing the Disk Operating
				System parts to a state of more or less basic functionality, work began on the Genetic Lifeform component.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GLADOS_LIVED">
			<Text>1998 - ???</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GLADOS_NAME">
			<Text>GLaDOS</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GLADOS_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Genetic Lifeform and Disk Operating System</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GLADOS">
			<Text>GLaDOS</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TURRET">
			<Text>Sentry Turret</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_TURRET">
			<Text>The Turret is cheap but defective.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_UNITS_MEDIEVAL_TURRET_TEXT">
			<Text>
				Sentry Turrets are miniature tripod robots that can open each side of their chassis (their 'arms') horizontally in order to reveal two gatling guns.
				The central part of the chassis holds their red eye, which emits a targeting laser. Almost all of the space within the Turret is devoted to storing the
				ridiculously stacked ammo, explaining the nearly infinite supply of ammo when firing.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When enemies are out of sight from the Turret's presence,
				they will maintain a standby state and will remain motionless with their guns retracted. Moving into their angle of sight however, will cause Turrets to
				deploy their guns shortly after greeting the unlucky individual before opening fire. They will continue to fire until the target is dead or moves away.
				If the latter occurs, Turrets will briefly search for the test subject (as indicated by the movement of the targeting laser), after which they will revert
				to a standby state.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TURRET_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Use Turrets only as a last resort, they are cheap but ultimatly useless</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_APT_0">
			<Text>Chell</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_APT_1">
			<Text>Doug Rattmann</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_APT_2">
			<Text>Cave Johnson</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_APT_3">
			<Text>Caroline</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_APT_4">
			<Text>Wheatley</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_APT_5">
			<Text>ATLAS</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_APT_6">
			<Text>P-body</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_APT">
			<Text>Less happiness but more Science for buildings and chances of great scientists.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_APT_SHORT">
			<Text>Science Initiative</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_APT_1">
			<Text>Effective Turret</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_APT_1_HELP">
			<Text>Increases movment, Heals and improves Bullets</Text>
		</Row>

		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_PEDIA_APT_1">
			<Text>Add text</Text>
		</Row>
		
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
